<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frederik Creemers</title>
    <link>https://www.frederikcreemers.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frederik Creemers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 22:27:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.frederikcreemers.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.frederikcreemers.be/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 22:27:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.frederikcreemers.be/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me.</title>
      <link>https://www.frederikcreemers.be/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 17:25:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.frederikcreemers.be/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m never sure what to put in &amp;ldquo;bio&amp;rdquo; sections on websites, let alone the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; page on my own site. If there&amp;rsquo;s something you want to know about me, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_bigblind&#34;&gt;just ask&lt;/a&gt;, and if it&amp;rsquo;s a question I get often, or I just find it particularly interested, I&amp;rsquo;ll add the answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;qa&#34;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-did-you-get-into-programming&#34;&gt;How did you get into programming?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was bored in class, I used to make little mouse-maze games using Microsoft powerpoint. This got me interested in making games, and I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yoyogames.com/gamemaker&#34;&gt;GameMaker&lt;/a&gt;, whic has its own programming language built in called GML. While at a book convention in Belgium, I picked up &amp;ldquo;PHP and MySQL for Dummies&amp;rdquo;, and that got me into web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-your-username-bigblind-are-you-a-poker-player&#34;&gt;Why is your username &amp;ldquo;bigblind&amp;rdquo;? Are you a poker player?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My username on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_bigblind&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bigblind&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and many other sites and platforms around the web, is &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;bigblind&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. This username came about the first time I played poker. I played with my newhew and a couple of his friends, and the first time I was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blind_(poker)&#34;&gt;big blind&lt;/a&gt;, we all laughed about it, because I&amp;rsquo;m visually impaired, and not in any dimension a small guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-what-way-are-you-visually-impaired&#34;&gt;In what way are you visually impaired?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have dysplasia of the optic nerve. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure hot to express what I see and what I don&amp;rsquo;t, because I don&amp;rsquo;t know a percentage or measure to express it, and I&amp;rsquo;ve never had &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; vision, so I have nothing to compare it to. I see almost nothing through my right eye, and quite a lot through my let eye (althoug I&amp;rsquo;m told compared to normal sight, it&amp;rsquo;s still quite little).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still see enough to visually find my way around places, although I do use a cane, bot to eel steps and other obstacles, and to signal my impairment to others. On a computer, I usually use a screen magnifier to enlarge whatever is on the screen. on my phone I use a combination of the magnifier ad VoiceOver (IOS&amp;rsquo;s screen reader).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>